Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/farhancdr (LinkedIn) farhancdr.github.io (Personal)

Top Skills

Amazon Dynamodb NestJS TypeScript

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Certifications

Software Engineer Internship
NodeJs (Basic)
Introduction to Programming Using
JavaScript
React (Basic)

Honors-Awards

Winner of PCIU Intradepartmental Programming Contest - 2021

Farhan Sadek Sakib

Software Engineer || Obsessed with back-end technologies || Javascript, Typescript, React, NodeJS, Express, NestJs, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, TypeORM

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Summary

A software engineer who is passionate about making software that makes people's lives better.

I am currently working as a software engineer at TECHZU. At TECHZU, I am working with Javascript, React, NodeJS, Express, and PostgreSQL. I always try to write clean and maintainable code in ways that make it easy to understand and maintain.

I also have working experience as a software engineer intern at Sohopathi, which is the first social learning platform in Bangladesh for peer-to-peer learning. During my internship period, I have worked with typescript, react, express, and mongodb. I've contributed to a React Dashboard project for managing students and online exams/ lectures. I've also developed a latex equation editor for making any kind of mathematical equation with just a few clicks. Some of the backend APIs and swagger documentation were also developed by me.

I have a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from Port City International University. While I was taking the bachelor's degree, I was a fan of competitive programming. The majority of my time was spent completing coding challenges for various online judges and competing in both online and onsite coding competitions. I have solved 1000+ ds/algo problems using various online judges. Solving these kinds of problems has helped me to improve my analytical skills and problem-solving skills.

After my work hours, I spend my time reading Islamic books, giving dawah to people, and playing with my cat.

Experience

Vivasoft Limited
Junior Software Engineer
October 2022 - Present (3 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Flarie

Junior Software Engineer October 2022 - Present (3 months)

Sweden

Technologies: Typescript, NestJs, MySQL, DynamoDB, TypeORM

Techzu

Junior Software Engineer May 2022 - October 2022 (6 months) Singapore

- Worked with ReactJs, Redux-toolkit, ExpressJs, NodeJs, PostgreSQL and Sequelize.
- Built a react-component library on top of material-ui, which is being used by many of their projects.
- Built a live-chat service (both ui and backend) with twilio api.
- Added complex filtering options for more than 6 api endpoints.

Sohopathi

Software Engineer Intern
December 2021 - April 2022 (5 months)

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Worked with reactjs, typescript and expressjs.
- Contributed to a react dashboard project for managing students and online exams/lectures.
- Created a latex equation editor with react-katex that can create any type of equation with a few clicks.
- Customized various backend api controllers as needed to integrate with the frontend app.
- Wrote API documentation with Swagger

Ayaat

UI Developer

October 2016 - January 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Chattogram, Bangladesh

Worked as a UI designer! My responsibility was to create social media banner, web banner, logos, product labels etc.

Education

Port City International University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (January 2018 - February 2022)

Patiya Govt College, Chittagong

Higer Secondary Education, General Science · (2014 - 2016)